Register of the Allan E. Goodman papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Allan E. Goodman papers
1947-1982
1965-1975
75001
Hoover Institution Archives
131 manuscript boxes, 2 card file boxes, 2 oversize boxes, 7 envelopes (56.6 linear feet)
Writings, reports, correspondence, clippings, notes, interviews, and printed matter, relating to the Vietnamese War, the Paris peace talks of 1968-1973, elections in South Vietnam from 1967 to 1971, the South Vietnamese legislature, migration to Saigon, urbanization and political and demographic change in Southeast Asia, counterinsurgency, and Soviet-American detente.
Goodman, Allan E., 1944-
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1975 with several increments received periodically until 1996.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1944 Born, New York City
1966 B.S., Northwestern University
1967-1971 Consultant on Vietnamese Affairs, U.S. Department of State and RAND Corporation
1968 M.P.A., John F. Kennedy School of Government, Harvard University
1970-1974 Professor of Government and International Relations and Department Chairman, Clark University
1971 Ph.D., Harvard University
1972 Editor, Indochina in Conflict: A Political Assessment (D.C., Heath, Lexington, Massachusetts)
1973 Author, Politics in War: The Bases of Political Community in South Vietnam
1974-1975 National Fellow, Hoover Institution on War, Revolution and Peace
1975-1980 Office of Political Research, Central Intelligence Agency
1978 Author, The Lost Peace: America's Search for a Negotiated Settlement of the Vietnam War
1978 Editor, Negotiating While Fighting: Diary of Admiral C.Turner Joy at the Korean Armistice Conference
1998-Present President, CEO & Advisor at the Institute of International Education, Inc.
Scope and Contents Note
Writings, reports, correspondence, clippings, notes, interviews, and printed matter relating to the Vietnam War, the Paris peace talks of 1968-1973, elections in South Vietnam from 1967 to 1971, the South Vietnamese legislature, migration to Saigon, urbanization and political and demographic change in Southeast Asia, counterinsurgency, and Soviet-American detente.
Rand corporation.; United States. Dept. of State.; Elections--Vietnam.; Guerrilla warfare.; Legislative bodies--Vietnam.; Rural-urban migration--Asia, Southeastern.; Rural-urban migration--Vietnam.; Urbanization--Asia, Southeastern.; Vietnamese Conflict, 1961-1975.; Asia, Southeastern.; Asia, Southeastern--Politics and government.; Saigon (Vietnam); Soviet Union.; Russia (Federation); Soviet Union--Foreign relations--United States.; United States--Foreign relations.; United States--Armed Forces.; United States--Foreign relations--Soviet Union.; Vietnam.; Vietnam--Politics and government.
- SUBJECT FILE, 1954-1975 (Boxes 1-25)
  Scope and Contents note
  Memoranda, reports, notes, correspondence, and clippings, arranged alphabetically by subject. See also 1975 Increment and 1976-1996 Increments.
  - Cambodian invasion (Box 1)
  - Cao Dai
  - Cap Tien
  - Chau, Tran Nguoc, case
  - Chieu Hoi (Open Arms) Program
  - Chinh, Truong
  - Civil Operations and Rural Developent Support (CORDS) Program
  - Dai Viet Revolutionary Party
  - Diplomats
  - Doan Ket (National Reconciliation) Program
  - Ho Chi Minh
  - Hoa Hao Social Democratic Party
  - Hoover Commission on Organization of the Executive Branch of the Government
  - International interactional analysis
  - Kissinger, Henry A.
  - Laotian invasion
  - Minh, General Duong Van ("Big") Minh
  - Miscellaneous
  - Montagnards
  - Nixon, Richard M.
  - Paris Agreement, 1973 (Box 2)
    - Allegations of Communist violations
    - Allegations of U.S. and South Vietnamese violations
    - Assessment
    - Implementation
      - General
      - Assessment
      - Cambodia
      - Cease-fire
        - General
        - Maps
      - Follow-up meetings, 1973
      - Laos
      - North Vietnamese troop withdrawal
      - U.S. expectations
  - Paris peace talks
    - 1969
    - 1970
    - 1972 June-October
    - 1972-1973
    - Draft agreement, 1972 October (Box 3)
      - NLF views
      - North Vietnamese views
      - South Vietnamese views
      - U.S. views
    - Effects of military developments upon negotiations
    - Preparations
      - General
      - North Vietnamese views
      - South Vietnamese views
    - Transcripts of NLF statements, January 25, 1969 to January 18, 1973 (Box 4)
    - Transcripts of North Vietnamese statements, May 13 to October 30, 1968
    - Transcripts of North Vietnamese statements, January 25, 1969 to January 18, 1973
    - Transcripts of South Vietnamese statements, January 25, 1969 to January 18, 1973 (Box 5)
    - Transcripts of U.S. statements, May 13, 1968 to January 18, 1973
  - Parliamentary systems
  - Pham Viet Tung
  - Philippines, agriculture
  - Press summaries (Box 6)
    - North Vietnamese, January 10 to October 31, 1969
    - South Vietnamese, August 12 to October 28, 1969
    - South Vietnamese, November 6, 1969 to March 15, 1971 (Box 7)
  - RAND Corporation (Box 8)
  - Saigon
    - Chamber of Commerce
    - Map
  - Southeast Asia, effects of conflict on migration
  - Soviet-American detente, interactional analysis
  - Stilwell, General Joseph W.
  - Tan Dai Viet Party
  - Thieu, Nguyen Van
  - U.S.
    - Aid to South Vietnam, 1974-1975
    - Anti-war movement
    - Defense budget
    - Development Mission
    - Legality of involvement in Vietnam (Box 9)
    - Marine Corps
    - Policy in the Far East, chronology
    - Policy in Vietnam
      - General
      - 1964-1965
      - 1966-1968
      - 1969-1971
      - North Vietnamese assessment
    - Relations with South Vietnam
    - Supplemental assistance for South Vietnam, 1975
    - Treaties with South Vietnam
  - Viet Cong (Box 10)
    - General
    - Failures
    - Political infrastructure
    - Tactics
  - Vietnam
    - Bibliography
    - Chronology
    - Communism
    - Communism (Box 11)
    - Communism (Box 12)
    - Culture
    - Economy
    - Expatriates in France
    - Geneva settlement, 1954
    - History
    - International Commission of Control and Supervision
    - Lessons
    - Miscellany
    - Nationalism (Box 13)
    - Numismatics
    - Perception of problem
    - Reconstruction
    - Refugees (Box 14)
    - Reunification
  - Vietnam, North
    - Army
    - Diary of a soldier
    - Domestic conditions
    - Economy
    - Foreign policy
    - Government
    - Relations with NLF
    - Youth
  - Vietnam, South
    - Agriculture
    - Alliance for National, Democratic, and Peace Forces
    - Areas under government control (Box 15)
    - Buddhists
    - Catholics
    - Child Welfare
    - Chinese community
    - Civil service
    - Corruption
    - Domestic conditions
    - Due process
    - Due process and repression
    - Economy (Box 16)
    - Education
    - Elections (Box 17)
    - Farmers' association and labor
    - Foreign policy
    - Free world assistance
    - Government
    - Government (Box 18)
    - Khmer minority statute
    - Labor movement
    - Land reform
    - Law relating to protection of prisoners of war and civilians
    - Legislature (Box 19)
      - General
      - Biographical data on legislators
      - Internal rules of the Lower House
    - Local government
    - Local government (Box 20)
    - Negotiations with NLF
    - Political fronts
    - Political groups
    - Political opposition
    - Political party law
    - Political prisoners
    - Politics
    - Population
    - Press code
    - Proposals for accommodation with NLF (Box 21)
    - Provincial files
      - General
      - An Giang
      - Coastal I Corps
      - Coastal II Corps
      - Dalat
      - Da Nang
      - Dinh Tuong
      - Gia Dinh
      - Hue
      - Khanh Hoa
      - Kien Hoa
      - Long An (Box 22)
      - Mekong Delta
        - Communal group areas
        - Rural Buddhists
      - Phu Yen
      - Quang Ngai
      - Vinh Binh
      - Vinh Long
      - War zone areas in III Corps
    - Public works
    - Revolutionary Development Cadre
    - Social welfare
    - Special civil institutions
    - Students
    - Surveys
      - General
      - Long An Province
      - Saigon
    - Third Force (Box 23)
    - Universities and professors
    - Veterans and ARVN
    - Youth
  - Vietnam Popular Forces
  - Vietnam Quoc Dan Dang
  - Vietnam War
    - Damage
    - Developments, 1965-1969
    - Developments in, 1973
    - Developments in, 1974
    - Developments in, 1975
    - Easter offensive, April 1972 (Box 24)
    - Infiltration into South Vietnam
    - Khe Sanh battle, 1968
    - Mining of Haiphong Harbor
    - Pacification
    - Peace proposals
    - Phoenix operation
    - Tet offensive, January 1968
    - Tet II offensive, August 1968
    - U.S. bombing campaign (Box 25)
    - U.S. casualties
    - U.S. prisoners of war
  - Vietnamization
- CONFERENCE AND SEMINAR PROCEEDINGS, 1968-1975 (Boxes 25-26)
  Reports, notes, and transcripts, arranged alphabetically by conference or seminar title.
  - "Communist Movements and Regimes in Indochina," ad hoc seminar, Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group, New York, New York, 1974 September 30-October 2 (Box 25)
  - Conference on the Military Lessons of Vietnam, Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy, Tufts University, Medford, Massachusetts, 1974 May 3-4
  - "Educational Development in Vietnam," Education and Manpower Development Seminar, Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group, San Francisco, California, 1968 March 5-6
  - "Peasants, Land Reform, and Revolutionary Movements," Rural Development Panel Seminar, Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group, Savannah, Georgia, 1974 June 4-6
  - "Rural Local Government and Development Administration in Southeast Asia," Development Administration Panel Seminar, Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 1974 April 4-6
  - "Social Development Planning in Vietnam, Laos, and the Khmer Republic: An Assessment of Experiences," Vietnam, Laos, Khmer Panel Seminar, Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group, Hong Kong, 1975 January 2-4 (Box 26)
  - "Strengthening of the Planning Apparatus," Indonesia Panel Seminar, Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group, Bukittinggi, West Sumatra, 1974 September 13-16
  - "Vietnam: A Contemporary Reassessment," National War College, Washington, D.C., 1974 September 26
  - "Whatever Happened to the Super Powers?" 29th annual conference, World Affairs Council of Northern California, Asilomar, California, 1975 May 2-4
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1947-1975 (Boxes 26-37)
  Drafts, notes, data, correspondence, and printed copies of speeches and writings, arranged alphabetically by author and under author by title. See also 1975 Increment and 1976-1996 Increments.
  - Atkyns, Glenn Chadwick, "Secondary Education: Nation Building in Vietnam,", 1968 (Box 26)
  - Aydelotte, William O., "The Disintegration of the Conservative Party in the Eighteen-Forties: A Study of Political Attitudes,", 1969
  - Beaumont, Jacques, and Martin Sandberg, "Programme Notes from a Visit to the Democratic Republic of Vietnam (DRVN) on 30 June - 7 July 1973,", undated
  - Beck, Carl, "Biography and the Analysis of Leadership in Communist Political Systems,", 1969
  - Brickman, Philip, Phillip Shaver, and Peter Archibald, "American Tactics and American Goals in Vietnam as Perceived by Social Scientists,", 1968
  - Brown, MacAlister, and Joseph J. Zasloff, "The Pathet Lao and the Politics of Reconciliation in Laos,", 1974
  - Chau, Phan Thien, "Political Development in the Democratic Republic of Viet Nam: The Politics of Survival and Nation-Building through Mass Mobilization,", 1973
  - Chau, Phan Thien, "Vietnamese Communism: A Bibliographic Essay,", 1974
  - Chen, Pi-chao, "The 'Planned Birth' Program of the People's Republic of China, with a Brief Analysis of Its Transferability,", 1974
  - Cua, Van Van, "Effects of the Western Civilization on the Vietnamese Society,", undated
  - Dean, John G., "Current French Policy toward Vietnam,", 1970
  - Donnell, John C., Guy J. Pauker and Joseph J. Zasloff, "Viet Cong Motivation and Morale in 1964: A Preliminary Report,", 1965
  - Dunn, Lewis A., "The Limits of Foreign Policy: Fear, Trembling and the Idealistic Impulse,", 1973
  - Elliott, David W. P., "Political Integration in North Vietnam: The Cooperativization Period,", 1974
  - Elliott, David W. P. and W. A. Stewart, "Pacification and the Viet Cong System in Dinh Tuong: 1966-1967,", 1968
  - Ellsberg, Daniel, "Impact of the VC Winter-Spring Offensive,", 1968 (Box 27)
  - Ellsberg, Daniel, "Some Lessons from Failure in Vietnam,", 1968
  - Frizzell, Lieutenant Colonel Donaldson D., "Air Power Vietnam: 1972", 1974
  - Gallucci, Robert L., "United States Military Policy in Vietnam: A View from the Bureaucratic Perspective," Ph.D. dissertation, Brandeis University, 1973
  - Giau, Tran Van, "South Vietnam Keeps Firm the Copper Wall," translated from the Vietnamese by Tran Van Dinh, 1967
  - Goodman, Allan E.
    - "America's Failure in Indochina,", undated
    - "Bases of Conflict and Accommodation within a Legislative Elite in South Vietnam,", 1971
    - "Beyond the New Isolationism,", undated
    - "The Causes and Consequences of Détente, 1949-1973,", undated
    - "Choosing Future Vice Presidents,", 1974
    - "Costs of Shuttle Diplomacy,", undated
    - "Demographic Aspects of Insurgency: The Case of Thailand,", 1967 (Box 28)
    - "Détente: The Road Ahead,", undated
    - "Diplomatic and Strategic Outcomes of the Conflict,", 1968
    - "End of the War as a Setting for Post-War Development in South Vietnam,", 1970
    - "End of the War as a Setting for the Future Development of South Vietnam,", 1971
    - "Ethnopolitics in South Vietnam,", 1967
    - "Fighting While Negotiating: The View from Hanoi,", undated
    - "Leaving the Future Up for Grabs: The Political Consequences of the Vietnam Cease-fire,", 1973 (Box 29)
    - "The Legacy of Resignation,", 1974
    - "The Lost Peace: Negotiating While Fighting in Vietnam, 1964-1974,"
      - Grant applications
      - Research travel
      - Outline
      - Chronology
      - Introduction
      - Chapter 1
      - Chapter 2
      - Chapter 3
      - Chapter 4
      - Chapter 5 (Box 30)
      - Chapter 6
      - Chapter 7
      - Chapter 8
      - Deletions
      - Postscript
      - Glossary
      - Biographical appendix
    - "Notes on the Administration of Elections in South Vietnam,", 1967
    - "Redeeming the American Pledge of Postwar Assistance for Vietnam,", undated
    - "Remember Vietnam?,", n.d.
    - Review of Jay Taylor, China and Southeast Asia: Peking's Relations with Revolutionary Movements, undated
    - "Secret Search for Peace,", undated
    - "South Vietnam: War without End?,", 1974
    - "South Vietnam's Military Politics: A Basis for Government?,", 1969
    - Speech at Boalt Hall Law School Forum, University of California, Berkeley, 1975 April 23
    - Speech to civic clubs, undated
    - "Towards a Political Settlement in Vietnam,", 1974
    - "U.S. Withdrawal: Its Effect on South Vietnamese Politics,", 1970 (Box 31)
    - "Vietnam and the Limits of Scholarly Intervention,", 1973
    - "Villagism and Communalism in South Vietnam,", undated
    - "What's Happening in Paris?,", undated
    - "Why Post-War Aid?,", undated
    - "Will the Vietnam War End?,", undated
  - Goodman, Allan E., and Lawrence M. Franks, "The Dynamics of Migration to Saigon, 1964-1972,", 1975
    - Drafts and notes
    - Data
    - Data format code
  - Goodman, Allan E., and Lawrence M. Franks, "Neither War nor Peace: The Causes and Consequences of Migration to Saigon, Vietnam,", 1973 (Box 32)
    - Manuscript
    - Manuscript draft
    - Preliminary thesis
    - Outlines
    - Research plans and design
    - Chapter on methodology
    - Chapter on problems and issues
    - Chapter on causes of migration
    - Chapter on consequences of migration
    - Notes
    - Questionnaire (Box 33)
    - Maps
  - Goure, Leon, "Some Thoughts on Infiltration and the Vietnam Settlement,", 1969
  - Gourou, Pierre, "The Future of Indochina,", 1947
  - Grant, James P., statement before the House Foreign Affairs Committee, March 26, 1968
  - Grinter, Lawrence E., "Bargaining between Saigon and Washington: Dilemmas of Linkage Politics During War,", 1974
  - Halperin, Morton H., "The Lessons Nixon Learned,", undated
  - Harris, Fred, "Elementary Education in South Vietnam,", 1968
  - Hickey, Gerald C., "Accommodation in South Vietnam: The Key to Sociopolitical Solidarity,", 1967
  - Hien, Nguyen Van, "North Vietnam's Foreign Policy: The Politics of Milieu,", undated
  - Hoan, Buu, "The Agonizing Transition, 1970-1975,"
  - Hoan, Buu, "Aid Strategy and the Postwar Reconstruction of South Vietnam,", 1970
  - Howard, Nigel, "Metagame Analysis of Vietnam Policy,", undated
  - Huntington, Samuel P., "Getting Ready for Political Competition in South Vietnam,", 1969
  - Huntington, Samuel P., "The Viet Cong in the Cities,", 1968
  - Huntington, Samuel P., and Allan E. Goodman, "South Vietnam After the War: The Politics of Neither War Nor Peace,", 1972
    - Introduction and outline
    - Chapter 2, "Politics within a New Constitutional Framework"
    - Chapter 3, "Impact of American Development Mission on Political Change"
    - Chapter 4, "Events and Developments"
    - Notes and drafts (Box 34)
    - Correspondence
  - Hutabarat, Panangaran, "An Estimation of Gross Value Added of Electricity, Gas, and Water Supply and of Ownership of Dwelling in the Province of South Sumatra in 1970,", 1972
  - Hutabarat, Panangaran, "The Estimation of Value Added in Finance Sector of South Sumatra, Indonesia, 1970,", 1972
  - International Bank for Reconstruction and Development, International Development Association, "Current Economic Position and Prospects of the Republic of Vietnam,", 1974
  - Jenkins, Brian Michael, "People's Army, Part III: Don Dien,", 1971
  - Kang, Young Hoon, "The Military-Security Implications of the North-South Korean Dialogue,", 1974
  - Kattenburg, Paul M., "The DRV's External Policies and Relations in the New Revolutionary Phase,", 1974
  - Kimin, Basir, "The Service Sector of South Sumatra, 1970,", 1972
  - Kirk, Donald, "The Khmer Rouge: Revolutionaries or Terrorists?,", 1974
  - Komer, R. W., "Was There Another Way?: Pacification as an Alternative Strategy in Vietnam,", undated
  - Koon, R. E., "Gradualism: A Chronology of Vietnam,", 1968
  - Lansdale, Major General Edward G., "Some Thoughts on Strategy in the Vietnam War,", 1973
  - Lautenschlaeger, Karl, "The Military Lessons of the Vietnam War: U.S. Carrier Air Operations,", undated
  - Lee, Luke T., "Legal Aspects of Implementing a Total National Population Program,", 1974
  - LEKNAS-KYODAI, "The First Preliminary Report of the Economic Survey of South Sumatra: The Pilot Survey and Its Findings,", 1972
  - LEKNAS-KYODAI, "A Summary of Gross Provincial Product Estimation for South Sumatra Province, 1970,", 1972
  - London, Paul A., "A Structure of Compromise in Vietnam,", 1968
  - Luthan, Julian, "An Estimation of Gross Value Added of the Manufacturing and Construction Industries in the Province of South Sumatra in 1970,", 1972
  - Luthan, Julian, "Value Added of the Mining and Quarrying Industries in South Sumatra, 1970,", 1972
  - McCloskey, Representative Paul N., Jr., "Report, Vietnam Fact-Finding Trip, February 24 - March 3, 1975: The North Vietnam-South Vietnam Confrontation,"
  - McLennan, Barbara N., "American Approaches to International Negotiation: Recent Patterns in Senate Opinion and Voting,", 1973
  - Marshall, S. L. A., speech, undated
  - Martin, Ambassador Graham, statement before the Senate Foreign Relations Committee, 1974 July 25
  - Menges, Constantine, "Colonel Chau on Pacification and Politics and in South Vietnam,", 1968
  - Menges, Constantine, "A Viet Cong Victory, 1968-1969: The International Consequences,"
  - "Military Lessons from Vietnam: Vietnam Strategy, 1964-1968,", undated (Box 35)
  - Milsted, Jerrold K., "An Overview of Certain Defense Research and Analysis in the Vietnam War, 1960-1972," speech at Senior Research Seminar in International Security Studies, Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy, Tufts University, Medford, Mass., 1973 November 21
  - Milstein, Jeffrey S., and William C. Mitchell, "Dynamics of the Vietnam Conflict: A Quantitative Analysis and Predictive Computer Simulation,", 1968
  - Nooter, Robert H., statement before the Senate Foreign Relations Committee, 1974 June 21
  - Pauker, Guy J., "A Proposal on How to End the War in Vietnam: The Case for an Asian Peace-Keeping Force,", 1968
  - Pearce, R. Michael, "Revolutionary War in Vietnamese Villages: Changes in Land Tenure and Political Authority,", 1968
  - "The Pentagon Papers: Three Editions Reviewed at the Cease-Fire,", 1973
  - Pike, Douglas, "Life in North Vietnam: Part One,", 1972
  - Pike, Douglas, "When the Communists Come,", 1972
  - Pohle, Victoria, "The Viet Cong in Saigon: Political Tactics and Popular Reactions during the Tet Offensive, 1968,"
  - Pool, Ithiel de Sola, "Cambodia and Viet Nam: A Moderate Statement,", 1970
  - Poole, Peter A., "The Khmer Resistance: An Internal Perspective,", 1974
  - Race, Jeffrey, "How They Won,", 1970
  - Raksasataya, Amara, "Foreign Aid to Public Administration in Thailand in the 1980s,", 1974
  - Ravenal, Earl C., "The Strategic Lessons of Vietnam,", 1973
  - Reuber, Grant L., "Some Aspects of Private Direct Investment in Developing Countries,", 1974
  - Rondinelli, Dennis A., and H. Raymond Radosevich, "The Seminal Role of Project Identification in Development Administration,", 1974
  - Sananikone, Phouangphanh, and Hongsa Chanthavong, "Country Paper: Laos,", 1974
  - Schottland, Charles I., "The Concept of Social Development,", 1975
  - Schulz, Ann, and Allen E. Goodman, "A World Restored? Negotiation and the Bases of Peace in Vietnam and the Middle East,", 1974
  - Scott, James C., "Exploitation in Rural Class Relations: A Victim's Perspective,", 1974 (Box 36)
  - Silverman, Jerry Mark, "Aspects of Village Administration in South Vietnam,", 1974
  - Silverman, Jerry Mark, "South Vietnam and the Elusive Peace,", 1973
  - Silverman, Jerry Mark, "South Vietnam and the Return to Political Struggle,", 1974
  - Simon, Sheldon W., "The Khmer Resistance: External Relations,", 1974
  - Siregar, Muchtarudin and Januar Batubara, "The Estimation of Value Added of the Transport and Communications Sector in South Sumatra in 1970,", 1972
  - Tai, Ta Van, and Jerry Mark Silverman, "The Persistence of Continuity in Transition,", 1973
  - Tamba, J. L., "Estimation of Regional Income Originating from the Government Sector in South Sumatra, 1970,", 1972
  - Thayer, Carlyle A., "Origins of the National Front for the Liberation of South Vietnam, 1954-1960: Debate on Unification within the Vietnam Workers' Party,", 1974
  - Thayer, Thomas C., "Patterns of the French and American Military Experiences in Vietnam,", undated